Bayu Faturahman

(Sofware Engginer)

OBJECTIVE

My diverse experience in IT (e.g. programming, software architecture, user experience designer, web developer, etc) stems from a simple desire to empower people's lives with computing technology. The world is getting smaller and smaller by the day. Geographic boundaries are disappearing; cultural differences fade. Humanity will gather together. That's what drives me: helping pave the way to an empowered global society.

Contact Information

Email: bayu.faturahman8@gmail.com

Linkind: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bayu-faturahman-8906a3196

Github: https://github.com/BayuFaturahman

EDUCATION

UIKA, Teknik Informatika S1

RELATED EXPERIENCES

Freelance (Flutter Developer, Mobile Developer), 2018-2020 PT.Mareca (Sofware House)

- Dev Apps Bjbs (https://play.google.com/store/search?q=bjbs&c=apps)
- Dev Apps Pospay (https://play.google.com/store/search?q=pospay&c=apps)
- Dev Mega Syariah (https://play.google.com/store/search?q=mega%20syariah&c=apps)

Responsibilities

- 1. Arrange development schedule and tickets for development (Fullstact).
- 2. Arrange demo progress schedule.
- 3. Assign tickets and milestone to developers.
- 4. Writing app skeleton.
- 5. Sending report progress on daily report
- 6. Tech: Flutter

Web Devekloper, PT. Media Telematika Jaya (2020 -2021)

Bareskrim Porli - Pusat Kriminalitas Nasional

Responsibilities:

- 1. Arrange development schedule and tickets for development.
- 2. Arrange demo progress schedule.
- 3. Assign tickets and milestones to developers.
- 4. Task breakdown.
- 5. Sprint Scope of Work (SOW) estimation.
- 6. Writing app skeleton to be used by other developers.
- 7. Prepare a library to be used.
- 8. Make sure all the communication is effective and efficient among developers involved.
- 9. Review code and merge to master branch after developers push to Git repository
- 10. Work in tandem with other developers to resolve tickets on time.
- 11. Deploy to staging and production servers.
- 12. Tech: Java, Jquery, SQL

Freelance (Flutter Developer, Mobile Developer), 2021-2022

Robust Creative (Sofware House)

Responsibilities

- 7. Arrange development schedule and tickets for development (Fullstact).
- 8. Arrange demo progress schedule.
- 9. Assign tickets and milestone to developers.
- 10. Writing app skeleton.
- 11. Sending report progress on daily report
- 12. Prepare library to be used.
- 13. Deployment.
- 14. Tech: Flutter, Firebase

Mobile Developer, PT Bank Negara Indonesia (2021-2022)

BNI Remitance App - Apliaction for send money (Japan)

Responsibilities

- 1. Develop application based on client requirements.
- 2. Troubleshoot and fix bugs.
- 3. Patching and upgrading system.
- 4. Send progress report, make suggestions and discuss the task with client's Project Manager.
- 5. Deployment
- 6. Tech: Flutter

Mobile Developer, PT Rantai Pasok Tenknologi (2022-2022)

WMS App - Aplication for suply chain enterprise

Link Play Store: (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fishlog.wms)

Responsibilities

- 7. Develop application based on client requirements.
- 8. Troubleshoot and fix bugs.
- 9. Patching and upgrading system.
- 10. Send progress report, make suggestions and discuss the task with client's Project Manager.
- 11. Deployment
- 12. Tech: Flutter

Freelance (Flutter Developer, Mobile Developer), 2022-2023

- Dev Apps Asistenku (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.MitraAsisten)
- Dev Apps Web Eksam (https://panduan.eksam.id/mengikuti-tryout-gratis-eksam.id)
- Dev Fullstack Web (https://www.labellaonlinestore.com/)
- Dev Fullstack Web (https://kansa.id/)
- Dev Apps Biomed (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bionmed-app)
- Dev M Biomed(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bionmed.bionmed)

Responsibilities

- 13. Develop application based on client requirements.
- 14. Troubleshoot and fix bugs.
- 15. Patching and upgrading system.
- 16. Send progress report, make suggestions and discuss the task with client's Project Manager.
- 17. Deployment
- 18. Tech: Flutter

RELATED SKILLS

Backend Framework : PHP (Laravel, Codelgniter), Java (Springboot), Python (Flask)
Frontend Framework : JQuery, React JS (Next. Js, Vite. Js), Vue. js, Flutter, Typescript

• Mobile : Android Native (Java, Kotlin), iOS Native (Swift),

React Native, Flutter

API Gateway : WSO2, Zuul, Kong, NginX+

• Database : MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MariaDB

• Web Server : Apache2, NginX

• Cloud Service : AWS, AlibabaCloud, Google Cloud Platform, Azure

• Repository Control : GIT, SVN

• Opera

• ting System : Windows, Windows Server, Mac OSX, Linux, Ubuntu, CentOS

• Container System : Docker